Now let's define a function for solving problems.
现在我们来定义一个函数 从而为问题求解
It's called Tree.Search because it superimposes a search tree
将函数命名为 Tree.Search 因为该函数将搜索树
over the state space.
叠加到了状态空间上
Here's how it works.
思路如下
Starts off by initializing the frontier to be the path
先把边缘初始化为路径
which consisting of only the initial state.
该路径将只包括初始状态
And then it goes into a loop in which it first check, see,
然后进入循环 循环会先进行检查
do we still have anything left in the frontier?
确认边界是否还有东西
If not, we fail.
如果没有 那么搜索失败
There can be no solution.
问题没有解
If we do have something, then we make a choice.
如果还有 那就进行选择
And Tree.Search is really a family of functions not a single algorithm
Tree. Search 实际上是个函数族 而不是单独的一个算法
which typically depends on how we make that choice.
算法的种类取决于我们如何执行 .choice 方法
And we'll see some of the options later.
至于选择我们稍后再讲
We go ahead and make a choice of one of the paths of the frontier and
继续 选择边界的一条路径
remove that path from the frontier.
将该路径从边界中取出
We find the state which is at the end of the path.
我们在路径末端找到状态
And if that state's a goal, then we're done.
如果这个状态就是目标 那我们就大功告成了
We've found a path to the goal.
我们找到了通往目标的路径
Otherwise, we do what's called expanding that path.
否则 我们就要扩展这条路径
We look at all the actions from that state, and
我们要搜索这个状态里的所有行动
we add to the path the actions and the result of that state.
然后将行动与状态结果添加到路径中
So we get a new path that has the old path, the action and
从而得到一条新路径 这样一来 新路径就包含了旧路径、行动
the result of that action.
和行动结果
And we stick all of those paths back onto the frontier.
然后将这些路径都放回边缘里
Now, Tree.Search represents a whole family of algorithms.
现在 Tree. Search 代表的是整个算法族
And where you get the family resemblance is that they're all looking at
而家族相似性就在于所有算法都会搜索边缘、
the frontier, popping items off and looking to see if their Goal Test.
弹出元素并判断元素是否能通过目标测试
But where you get the difference is right here in the choice
而算法的不同则源自这里的选择
of how your going to expand the next item on the frontier,
与你决定如何扩展边缘的下一个元素有关
which path would you look at first.
也就是与你会先搜索哪条路径有关
And we'll go through the different sets of algorithms
我们来讲讲各种算法集
that make different choices for which path to look at first.
不同算法集会做出不同的选择 因此先搜索的路径会有所不同
The first algorithm we want to consider is called Breadth- First Search.
我想讲的第一个算法叫做宽度优先搜索
Now it could be called Shortest First Search because what it does is always
也可以叫最短优先搜索 因为该算法总能
choose off the frontier one of the paths that hasn't been considered yet
从边缘里取出一条尚未考虑到的路径
that's the shortest possible.
而且这条路径会是最短的
So how does it work?
算法原理是怎样的呢？
Well, we start off with the path of length zero starting in the start state.
我们先从长度为零 也就是从初始状态出发的路径开始
And that's the only path in the frontier so its the shortest one, so we pick it.
这是边缘唯一的一条路径 所以是最短的 因此我们就选该路径
And then we expand it and
将其扩展开来
we add in all the paths that result from applying all the possible actions.
应用所有可能行动 将所得的所有路径加进来
So now we've removed this path from the frontier, but
现在我们将这条路径从边缘中取出
we've added in three new paths.
并加入三条新路径
This one, this one, and this one.
这条 这条和这条
Now we're in a position where we have three paths on the frontier, and
现在我们所处的位置在边缘有三条路径
we have to pick the shortest one.
我们要挑最短的一条
Now, in this case, all three paths have the same length, length one, so
而这里三条路径长度都相同 都为 1
we break the tie at random, or using some other technique.
所以我们随机挑一条 或者用其它技巧从中挑一条
And let's suppose that in this case, we choose this path from here to Sibiu.
假设我们选了这条路径 从这里到锡比乌(Sibiu)(Sibiu)
Now, the question I want you to answer is,
现在我想请问
once we remove that from the frontier, what paths are we going to add next?
将这条路径从边缘取出后 下一步要加入什么路径呢？
So show me by checking off the cities that ends the paths,
请勾选路径末端的城市 告诉我
which paths are going to be added to the frontier?
要往边缘加入哪条路径？